Dzmitry Biruk

Senior Frontend Developer

Summary

Frontend Developer with **7 years** of experience specializing in in **React**, **TypeScript**, and **JavaScript**.

Worked in both large and small teams, contributing to cutting-edge and legacy applications. Started several apps from scratch.

Developed a small MVP and successfully transformed it into a usable product. Believe that effective communication is key to solving any problem.

Details

English B2 biruk.d@hotmail.com LinkedIn

Experience

Senior Frontend Developer, Tech Lead at Leroy Merlin

Sep 2023 - Present

- Started, developed, and deployed the MVP for the app.
- Provided technical expertise in the initial app analysis and task creation.
- Established FE architecture in the team.
- Developed and integrated a new microfrontend into the main app.

Senior Frontend Developer at Leroy Merlin

Jul 2022 - Sep 2023

- Started splitting a high-load legacy app into micro-frontends and rewriting it from Flow to TypeScript.
- Developed several new micro-frontends with Webpack Module Federation.
- Refactored and optimized legacy BFF endpoints, resulting in a 30% speed improvement.
- Developed several pages for the main app.

Senior Frontend Developer at EPAM

Apr 2022 - June 2022

Contractor for EF Tours. Switzerland. Short-term project.

- Developed a new page to a legacy trip planning app.
- Improved trip planning algorithm to fit business requirements

Senior Frontend Developer at EPAM

Nov 2020 - Mar 2022

Contractor for TVH. Waregem, Belgium.

Developed and launched Proof of Concept and then MVP for a new contact center using Twilio and React. It includes:

- A complex routing system to direct calls to the appropriate agent with support for 4 languages.
- Lambda functions for logic and integration with SalesForce for customer data.
- A React app to display customer data for agents.

Started a new order management app:

- Created pages for order creation and display.
- Implemented a role-based authentication system with JWT.

Frontend Developer at EPAM

Feb 2019 - Oct 2020

Contractor for HAVI. Chicago, USA.

- Developed 4 applications for different HAVI users.
- Participated in FE architecture development.
- Created several npm packages for HAVI apps (Login, Navigation).
- Improved app performance by reducing build sizes and implementing code splitting.
- Added logging and tracking tools.

Frontend Developer at EPAM

Jun 2018 - Feb 2019

Contractor for Edmunds. Santa Monica, USA.

- Developed a variety of user-interactive advertisement components.
- Implemented several content pages with React and JavaScript.

Junior Frontend Developer at EPAM

July 2017 - June 2018

Contractor for Edmunds. Santa Monica, USA.

- Developed new dealer pages for the main website with React and JavaScript.
- Removed usage of legacy image tool across all websites.

Skills

React, TypeScript, Redux, Webpack, Redux Toolkit, Redux-Saga, Redux-Thunk React Query, TanStack Query Bootstrap, Material-Ui, Css/Sass, Css in js, Jest, React Testing Library

Education

Bachelor, Belarusian National Technical University, Minsk 2013 - 2017